And where they are in overkill.
Not everything should be used everywhere. Multi-agent system have their specific use.
And there are some places where if you add a multi-agent system, you are just adding a lot of build to your.
Cloud Coast like to your API cost.
or you're bloating the system. So let's understand what a multi-agent system is.
By revising what agents are.
So we have… yesterday we learned about LandGraph, we learned about state, node, edges.
We learned how a permutation and combination of
This enables us to build multiple types of system.
Land graph, I would say, is kind of a language of its own.
So, just like you can have any language.
You can write a for loop, you can write, uh…
While loop you can write, you know, multiple.
sub-programs and everything.
You can do similar kind of things in LangGraph and build stateful systems.
We also learned about human in the loop.
How is it important and how to add it, how to implement it using LandGraph.
And then we learned about subgraphs.
So, how to take a complex workflow, how to break it down?
into multiple subgraphs, how to connect them together by mapping states.
And achieve the result.
We also learned about AI agent, which is a program.
that takes input, thinks about it,
Acts to complete a task using tools.
memory and knowledge.
Can anybody tell me what particular loop it runs internally?
By now, I think most of you should know about it.
Yeah, the react loop.
Okay, so it reasons and it takes actions using tools.
It reasons using LLM, it acts using the tools that it has access to.
So this is what an AI agent would look like.
We will have an LLM, we will have tools, knowledge, memory, we'll provide the access of all of this to our LLM, and it will be able to execute tasks.
In a multi-agent system, you multiply this architecture.
And you create copies of these agents.
Each one specializing to do some specific task.
Can anybody give me an example of a multi-agent system?
Exactly. So in Claude Code.
You can run sub-agents, okay?
You can give the task of developing a website, and inside, Claude can also automatically decide that it needs to spin up some subagents and assign tasks.
And this helps in isolating context for a specific task.
Remember this word, isolating context, this will come back later on.
So…
Dividing an agent into sub-agent can isolate context for
Individual sub-agents.
Reducing the cognitive overload of an AI model, which means that the model would not have to think a lot for doing.
a smaller task, right? So…
It follows the methodology of divide and conquer.
And through multi-agent system, we observed
that we are able to solve complex problems.
That a single agent would not be able to solve.
But why do we need multi-agent?
Why do we need multi-agent systems?
The first and foremost reason for it is.
To scale S-Time compute.
How many of you have heard this term or read it on Twitter, read it on LinkedIn, Reddit.
Somewhere on news that
Engineers are trying to scale test-time compute of LLMs.
Anyone who knows this?
This became very popular when DeepSeek was launched.
So test and compute simply means that you do not
Spend a lot of money during training of the model.
I mean, you spend, but…
During training of the model, you train it to follow generic tasks.
But while testing,
You apply methods that do inferencing in such a way that model retrieves context in such a way.
That model is able to perform difficult wrong, long-running tasks.
Okay. So,
Scaling test time compute can be done using multi-agent system.
Because you can take a complex problem.
You can use multiple instances of the LLMs.
And during test time, like, during inferencing itself,
You can generate a lot more data through the LLM in those multi…
Multiple systems parallel.
To solve a complex problem.
Then you can get specialized agent to do specialized task.
Yesterday, you built different subgraphs, you build different kind of.
LangGraph workflows. Can you give me some example where you can have specialized agent or a team of specialized?
Agent to do any kind of task.
In the chat, folks, anybody would like to give example.
Of some workflow, yeah, research agent and summarize agent, exactly.
Booking agent is a great example. So, in Booking Agent,
You can build multiple sub-agents that can
Create your itinerary that can search.
affordable prices for you for hotels or planes.
Another agent that can book things for you, another agent that can update things for you.
All of those things, ok.
So, we can have specialized agent in a multi-agent system.
And we can also run agents parallel if we have multiple agents.
A good example of this is research agent. When we have a research agent.
We need to research on
a topic from multiple different sources.
Okay? And the greater our search.
Of spaces, the better the result is.
So we have to increase our search space, because of which we can run multiple different specialized sub-agents.
Let's say one is searching on YFinance, one is searching only on Google, one is searching only on
Some other website like Money Control, whatever.
And all of these agents then consolidate information, bring it in for, bring a consolidated information.
for the supervisor agent, that it can use
To later generate a
Thorough response. So parallelization is
possible when you have multiple agents.
Okay, these are all the benefits.
Can you guys list any other benefits that you may think of? Just think about it. Think about implementing it in your own system.
And let me know if you can think of any other benefits here, okay? Those who are watching the recording, you also.
Take a notepad and just write whatever I'm asking you to do.
Yeah, it can save time, not really, because
When you have a multi-agent system, it takes a lot of time.
So, let me talk about when to use a multi-agent system.
And when not to use a multi-agent system, ok, this is going to be important.
This is, you can take a screenshot of this slide later on.
This will help you design architecture.
Based on all of these criteria that we are talking about.
Okay, let us look at what the first criteria is.
When the task is straightforward, you should choose a single agent system.
Okay, because a multi-agent system.
Will be an overkill. But when the task is complex.
When you want to decompose a larger task into multiple smaller tasks.
At that time, building a multi-agent system makes a lot of sense.
Then we also need to care about speed and latency.
In single agent system.
Usually the execution time is low.
Because we have one LLM, we can, we have simple set of tools, they can run fast, there is no
So, try to understand every time you are handing off some tasks, every time a coordinator agent.
is handing off some task to a sub-agent.
At that particular time.
There is some token expense.
It also takes some time to delegate the task.
And that back and forth conversation.
consumes time and tokens.
We have to realize this.
Okay, so…
If you want faster execution,
Go for a single agent system.
If speed and latency is not a priority for you.
And if a single agent can hit context limit.
Then go for a multi-agent system.
Okay. When…
Cost is more important to you than performance. Go for a single agent system.
When accuracy is more important,
Then cost, go for a multi-agent system.
Okay. But remember,
Always, always start with a single agent system.
Okay, start with a single agent system.
Identify the limitations of it.
And then decide whether or not you need to.
Pivot to multi-agent system.
Okay, so take a screenshot of this. This slide is going to be really important for you.
To choose which kind of architecture you need to implement.
But remember, every time you start with a single agent system.
Scale it to a multi-agent system.
Based on all of these.
Thanks. I will answer one question from Sanmuk.
While using multi-agents, the accuracy of output increases because we dedicate specific work for agent, correct.
Okay, there was no question.
Alright, let's move on.
I'm going to talk briefly about
Different kinds of multi-agent architecture.
Now, I'm going to tell you one thing.
You can always create a custom architecture for yourself.
These are just the basic architectures that
Early AI engineers have come up with.
And I'm sharing to you because
Mostly, you will be using either of these architectures.
The simplest architecture is a sequential pattern.
In a sequential pattern, the sequential pattern is something that you implemented yesterday as well.
Okay. In a sequential pattern,
You have an agent that then you have
Ah.
Another agent that runs based on the output that the previous agent gives.
This agent will produce some output, give it to the
to another agent, and all of these executions, they happen one by one.
After everything has executed,
The sub-agent will give back the response to main agent.
And it will respond to the user.
An example of this is
the research agent that we saw.
So you have a research agent.
A research agent will generate a draft.
A review agent will review it.
A finalizer agent will finalize it and
Give you that graph. I'm going to take the same example.
and explain it in various different architectures as well.
Now, I'll stop for a while, I'll answer some questions. Meanwhile,
Can you guys tell me any other place where sequential agent would be useful?
And it's the right choice to make.
Because this agent is…
The agent in multi-agent systems that consumes least amount of resources.
And least amount of tokens.
Okay.
For similar use case, if you would design a hierarchical agent or some other kind of agent.
The delegation part will take a lot of… will consume a lot of tokens, back and forth. So it…
reduces that. Can you think of any application where this can be used?
I will take a question from Sanjeev.
Any scenario from you where you will choose single or multi-agent systems. Sanjeev, we will talk about it in the end, okay? By that time, I think you will come up with a few examples yourself.
Invoice processing and data extraction.
Plan a vacation, rack, code review. Yeah, code review agent can work like this.
Document reading, no, stock trading, no. Yeah, email generation agent can work like this, Nitesh.
Find a ticket, book ticket… yeah.
Trip multi-agent can work like this. Syed, yes.
Sai Shridam, production error no production error monitoring agent.
I don't think this is the right approach for production monitoring agent.
Okay, I see most of you understand this. I think ticket, ticket agent and email agent.
And, uh…
I think vacation planning agent, these all make sense.
Okay. Can you guys guess the next architecture?
It is a very famous one.
Parallel is there, parallel is there, but another one is coordinator region.
Okay? Coordinator agent.
So, in Coordinator agent, you have a boss agent.
Alright, and this boss agent will have
Multiple different subagents.
So, sub-agent A and subagent B will report to this coordinator agent.
Both of them will report to this coordinator agent.
Coordinator agent will dynamically choose.
Which agent to delegate the job to?
Okay, so this, like, this, yeah, master-slave pattern, exactly. So, this looks like
small team where there is a team lead,
And under the team lead, there are
Different workers and each worker
will specialize into something.
The team leader will assign the task.
Assess the output, modify it if needed.
And then delegate it to some other team.
So, coordinator agent.
is also a very popular pattern.
And, uh, both of them, like, will keep sending intermediate output to coordinator agent, ok.
Coordinator agent will keep asking, tell me, if you've done this, they will keep sharing with the coordinator agent.
They will not communicate with each other.
The coordinator will communicate with each of them.
All right, they will not communicate with each other, coordinator will communicate with each of them.
Yeah, each individual sub-agent that you see will be a React agent.
Okay, a React loop is running in each of these.
Square brackets, like square blocks that you see.
Alright, yeah, this is also known as orchestrator pattern because
The coordinator agent is orchestrating the workflow.
By delegating tasks to
Subagent 1 or subagent 2.
They can run in parallel if you have designed them to run in parallel.
But usually, they do not run in parallel because
The output of one agent may depend on the output of other.
In cases where
The output of one agent does not depend on the other. You can choose to run them parallel.
All right, so we can have a supervisor agent.
Which can delegate tasks to research researcher agent.
The researcher agent can ask information regarding a specific task.
like, specific topic to supervisor agent.
To write about it.
Supervisor agent can then delegate it to researcher agent. This can go on for a while.
Until they have finished and provided a result.
Okay, so this is coordinator pattern.
Now, when you scale this coordinator pattern,
Into multiple hierarchies.
Just like a real team, in a real team, there are multiple hierarchies, right?
So, you can have a coordinator agent.
We can head a sub, you can have a sub agent.
Each sub-agent can be coordinator of
Other subagents.
So, there is multiple level of hierarchy and agency among each of these.
This is the most expensive.
Architecture to build.
Because there is a lot of conversation going on between agents.
Can you guys give me…
An example of this kind of an agent.
It was very popular.
Recently.
And see, it was such a hype that almost everybody has forgotten about it.
Yeah, Anurak is on point, okay?
OpenClaw was one such agent. You can spin up like multiple sub-agents which can.
execute their own subagent.
Yeah, Claude workspaces can also do this, yes.
So open clock. And any example where this kind of workflow can make sense.
Marketing, yes, marketing.
So, anywhere,
Any system where you are trying to
Create.
Uh, digital twin of our company.
So let's say you want to build a marketing agent, you want to build a
A content creator agent, right.
In all of those cases, you can have
Agents like this.
And just give me one second, I will do one thing.
All right.
Yeah. Bug solver agent.
I think bug solver agent works well in a coordinator pattern.
But depending on what kind of application you have, you can use.
I had people.
Okay, so…
Here, you decompose tasks, like, at multiple layers.
And, uh…
Similarly, here you can have a supervisor agent, you can have a research agent, you can have a writer agent.
The research agent can have multiple agents depending on the platform.
You can have a Google research agent, you can have a money control research agent, you can have a
Why Finance Research Agent and all of them, so folks, there is no problem where you cannot.
Use either of these architectures.
Only thing is, where are they most suitable?
For example, I can build it like this, but do you think this is actually needed? I have overcomplicated this example.
Just to showcase to you. Okay, just to show you how
One simple use case can be
Turned into multiple architectures.
But tell me, do you give me a thumbs up if you think this is the appropriate architecture. Give me a thumbs down if you think this is an overkill.
Let's see. If you are able to make that judgment.
Yeah, I see thumbs down by Pawan.
Right? So, exactly, this is an overkill.
Yeah, I can have a coordinator pattern, simple coordinator pattern would work.
I don't even need a coordinator pattern, to be honest. A simple sequential pattern can work well for this.
So…
Makes sense if tasks are complex enough to be decomposed. Yeah, for example.
If I'm doing a simple research task,
This is not making sense.
But if I'm doing a frontier research,
For example, if I'm trying to research how to
Build new LLM architectures, or if I'm researching something on math,
I'm trying to solve a 100-year-old problem on math that nobody has been able to solve yet.
Then this kind of an architecture makes sense.
Okay?
Yeah, so always be mindful of the kind of architecture.
That you choose while building a multi-agent systems.
So…
Let's compare all of these patterns.
When should we use sequential? When should we use supervisor?
And when should we use hierarchical?
So…
Whenever the steps are always going to be
in the same order.
Whenever there is no
Dynamic execution that needs to happen.
In any workflow. At that time, you will choose the sequential pattern.
Whenever…
The right next step depends on the task and may loop or skip.
Which means that whenever
The next step that you need to do.
Depends on…
Some task, that is.
that somebody else is doing, somebody direct is doing.
And you need to communicate with them. At that time, supervisor makes sense.
But when you have multiple distinct domains.
Let's say you want to create a digital company.
Some people used to do that, right?
How many of you have heard of Crew AI?
CREW Trio AI.
I'm writing it in the chat.
Yeah, clearly, it became very popular because
People were able to at least.
Uh, seemingly.
They could create multiple sub-teams.
So, in those kind of things, CrewAI follows a hierarchical structure.
Uh, by default. So, in those kind of tasks, hierarchical structures make sense.
And number of workers is
few and fixed and here you can have, like,
At max, it is not 2. 2 is like the minimum amount.
But you can have 3 to 6
Different agents and supervisor, that is the typical average.
number of agents that they have.
In hierarchical, you can have many.
Okay, you can have many such subagents.
Sequential is the most predictable one.
It is less probabilistic in nature.
Supervisor has lower…
Predictability, but it is still better than hierarchical, ok.
Hierarchical has lowest amount of predictability.
Do you know why? Why hierarchical has lowest amount of credibility?
How many of you have played that game?
in your childhood, where you sit on a circle.
There is one person who whispers some word.
In the ears of the person next to him.
or her and that word passes through the circle. By the time it reaches to the first person.
The meaning totally changes, yeah? Chinese whispers.
That's what happens in hierarchical agentic pattern mostly, ok.
So, yeah.
Yeah, people are remembering their childhood, I see.
Okay. So, hierarchical architecture is
least predictable because of this reason.
If there is a simple amount of
context poisoning that happens in between the execution.
It can change the whole track of where the agent was going towards.
So it can even change your goal. So you have to be very careful. It has to be engineered really well.
If you're building a hierarchical agentic system, it has to be engineered really well.
And you need to apply, like, really thorough context engineering, something which we are going to learn.
later on. We are going to learn about context engineering later on.
But it becomes really important in case of hierarchical agent.
Okay, then cost and latency, I think I would ask to predict.
Tell me, which one will take highest amount of cost?
Yeah, so here as well we see the same pattern.
Sequential is usually like most budget friendly.
Supervisor is a bit expensive.
And, but I would say it's okay to use Supervisor if you are
Opting for higher accuracy for very complex task.
But choose hierarchical.
Like…
Be extra careful while choosing hierarchical architectures, ok, because
They are less predictable and they are very expensive.
It is easiest to debug sequential. It is a bit difficult to debug supervisor just because
You need to keep a track of the conversations, right?
It is hard to identify.
What is the cause of the error? It is hard to identify the point of failure.
In supervisor and the point of failure grows exponentially in
hierarchical agents.
Okay, it's okay, Sanjee, if you can take a snapshot while watching the recording.
So this is again comparing all the architecture.
If you want to take a screenshot, take a screenshot here.
All right. So, this is it. By the way, in the
Ashish may ensure that in the
Summary that we give to all of them.
We can we can include a screenshot of these two slides.
Alright, so…
This is a comparison between all of three patterns.
We are going to build our agent now.
I would…
Ask you all to first do a bit of setup.
Before doing it, but…
I'm telling you this is going to be.
A bit long, the class is going to be a bit long.
So before hands-on, I will take some Q&As. After taking some Q&As.
We can take a 10-minute break.
Okay. After that 10-minute break,
We can get back and do the hands-on.
Sandeep, they are not talking to each other.
They're not talking to each other. So Sandeep has asked how Chinese whispers
Example fits into hierarchical sub-agent, they talking to each other. That's called managers mess.
Yeah, but…
I'm telling that if there are multiple agents.
If one of the agent gets poisoned, context poisoned,
And it shares some irrelevant response.
To the manager agent, and you have not engineered it well.
That message can live in the history.
of the manager agent.
And it can tickle down into multiple sub-agents as well.
Okay, so…
That's how a simple…
Miscommunication between agents can
Go into, like, multiple ones.
It's supposed to have low latency since final results arrive after final route runs.
Wherein hierarchical, it is a pattern.
Saranganathan, yes, in hierarchical.
It all depends on the supervisor note when it is satisfied.
by response of all of these subagents.
And it takes time and compute, I said, right? It takes time and compute to communicate.
Everything between supervisor and all of these.
Sub-agents. So, that is why it is like most expensive and
It is also, uh,
It runs for a longer duration.
than the others.
Right, any other questions, anybody?
Supervisor and hierarchical can involve
Agents running in parallel, but it is totally up to you.
Okay, Amit, it is totally up to you.
You can choose whether or not to make them run in parallel.
Is it possible for an agent to lock in infinite loop?
It is very possible just a few weeks ago.
I was building something because of a simple mistake that I did.
While defining the middlewares.
My agent was stuck in an infinite loop.
So, it ran for around 16 minutes.
And I was using three Grok API, ok.
It was running for around 16 minutes.
Then I knew that something is fishy.
When I rechecked, I had to fix that middleware bug.
And then it was able to run properly.
So, agent can go in infinite loop, that is why you need to
Do all of these evaluations. You need to do cost evaluation, you need to do latency evaluation.
And then there are multiple accuracy valuations that you can make.
Can we get better results with lower models, but using hierarchical task decomposition architecture?
That was the whole idea behind it.
that we can have multiple sub-agents.
that use, uh…
cheaper model and a supervisor agent that uses a moderate model.
And together, they can perform really complex task.
At a lower cost. That was…
The idea behind it.
And most of the time it works.
Only thing is we need to engineer it really well. You need to ensure.
That context that is shared among all of these.
Different nodes in a multi-hierarchical system.
Is really well defined.
Can end be assigned to more than
One agent? Uh…
It really depends, like…
There are also architectures where you build a web of different agents.
Where each agent is able to communicate with the other.
Okay. And that kind of web like in that kind of architecture.
It is a, like, it is possible that multiple subagents can communicate with others. I told you, these are like
The most basic architectures, you can read about them more. Google has a really good blog around it.
I can share the link of that blog in Discord. That will be really useful to you.
In any architecture parallel.
Parallelism will be right because time.
Sai Krishna, parallelism can be good in supervisor and hierarchical depending on the task that you are performing.
But understand, it all depends on the business use case.
Okay, but in sequential.
In sequential, you are taking sequential architecture.
You're choosing it because you are assuming.
that the output of one agent is required by the other agent to start working.
Okay.
So in sequential, there is no scope of parallelization in my opinion.
Uh, you can have, you, you may have multiple sequential pipelines running in parallel.
But in that individual sequential pipeline,
You cannot have parallelism between different agents that are present because
One agent is expecting the output of other agent to start working.
How to know if the pattern you choose is correct or not? You know it based on
Comparison, experimentation, and evaluation.
So, that's why I said, always, in this case as well,
Always start with.
The simplest approach.
If they evaluate it, if the simplest approach is not
Uh, you know, performing as per your expectations in the evaluation.
Then move on to a complex architecture, ok. Gradually move on to the most complex one.
Don't start with the most complex one and then
decompose it to be…
You know, simpler.
What was the mistake? Just curious?
I was trying to minimize context propagation.
In my agentic loop.
And, uh, what I did was…
I used a summarizer agent.
Uh, but…
Like rather than summarizing, it was…
trimming most of the part of the output.
So because it was trimmed,
The main content.
that, like, the meat of…
The meat of the execution that came out.
Was being trimmed out.
Because it was trimmed out, the agent was thinking that the tool execution did not work out, so it was running again and again.
Renganathan is, I think, asking about the mistake that I made, so that's what I explained.
Loops in multi-agent system.
I'll tell you.
So when we write the code, no, you will understand.
See, each agent already is running in a loop.
Where an LLM is calling tools, it's observing them.
Pre-executing, ok, that is what is happening in the room.
When you scale it to multiple loops running in a mega loop,
You have a multi-agent system.
So, RK has asked a really interesting question. How do we decide which agent runs
After which one do we decide it using Landgraph and our use case?
So, based on whatever you have learned yesterday about building workflows,
Can you… can anybody answer Argy's question?
In the chat.
Yeah, conditional edges.
Exactly, conditional edges can help you route.
But through edges, you can decide the workflows. So each agent will be a node.
And the edges will decide which agent to execute after.
The previous agent?
And when you add it in a graph, you have an agentic workflow, ok, this is what we call an agentic workflow.
Where the main program is a workflow.
But internally, some nodes can be agentic in nature.
All right, so overall it is a workflow, but there are some parts where you are providing agency to the system.
In your experience, what supervisor agent you have used?
So in one of the companies that I worked for, we were building an agent that could solve
Uh, production box.
From traces.
In the initial architecture, we used a supervisor agent.
That, and we had multiple sub-agents, like, because we had multiple.
Observability platforms. So, one platform.
was for observing the system metrics. One platform was for observing logs.
And what one platform was for observing APM.
Okay, so for each of these we had individual agents that will
Isolate the cause of the problem.
And, uh.
Research about it and bring their research.
to the main agent. Main agent will try to identify the connection between all of the individual results.
And then prepare a plan for solution.
That solution will go to another agent which was a GitHub agent.
That GitHub agent would
Identify the root cause, like the exact line of root cause, because
You know, right, in stack trace, you get the exact line where the program failed.
So it will fetch the code from GitHub, it will fix it and publish it.
So this was a multi-agent system that we built.
And it was using supervisor pattern.
So actually, I would say it was using hierarchical pattern because
This supervisor was reporting to another one, the core one, the research supervisor.
And we had like multiple systems.
There was a research agent that would research all of these platforms to find out root cause. So it did RCA, it is called
root cause analysis agent.
And RC agent will then
Report back to supervisor, which will
The system architect will design a plan, it will go to the agent that will
Implement it on GitHub.
So I worked on a very initial part of this.
Uh, I think it was launched few months ago.
Not humans, I think it has been 8 months, some 8, 9 months now.
It was launched, it was, I think, top 3 in Product Hunt.
that particular feature.
What was the real scenario where an agent was creating an agent by itself?
Part of a real scenario is Claude code.
Claude code, open claw, all of these things, they have system Hermes agent.
All of these systems, they use this process of
Creating subagents and some agents.
Alright folks, I think I've answered most of your questions.
Let's take a 10-minute break.
After that, we will start the hands-on.
Uh, ensure that you are logged into your
GitHub. Okay.
Ensuring that you have a GitHub ID and you are logged into your GitHub.
And create any public.
Any public repository with any boilerplate code, just
have these things ready. I'm giving you a to-do. Do this in the break.
Okay. I am giving a to-do. Please do not write any anything in chat.
Okay, so folks, I've sent you a to-do. It is a very simple to-do.
Ashish, why can you share the PDF in the chat?
So, create a GitHub account,
Log into that account if you already have an account.
You don't need to create it.
Then create a dummy repository.
with few dummy files.
You can choose to vibe code a simple project.
And push it on your GitHub repository.
And go through the pre-read ones. I think you will need more time to do this, so let me give you a 15-minute break.
Take a 15-minute break, do this,
And then we will come back, ok. Ashish Bhair shared.
This give me a tick mark in this message, to-do message.
Once you are done, okay? If you're done with it,
Give me a tick mark, I will see that.
I want to ensure all of you have done this.
If you're, if you have completed these steps, then only you can follow.
Whatever the hands-on is.
Alright, Ashishmay, please start a timer for 15 minutes for break.
Renganathan, the GitHub agent setup steps is the pre-read.
Okay.
For folks, it's okay if you're done. You can utilize this break for…
uh, drinking water, whatever.
The main break that we will have will be smaller.
So, utilize this break.
Okay, those of you who have not.
Just take this.
Okay, uh, Bharat?
Whitenstone in Theos.
Thumbs down. Are you guys not done yet?
Okay, if you're stuck at step 2, it's totally fine.
Okay, only complete step 1.
Alright folks, so…
Let me share my screen.
The problem statement that we are going to solve today is very special.
We are going to create something similar to
This particular website you might have come across. How many of you know this? Code Rabbit?
This was the inspiration for creating.
This particular project.
Anybody have seen this?
Okay, so Code Rabbit is an agentic
platform, which integrates to your GitHub repository.
And can make code changes, review PRs, do all of those things automatically.
All right, this existed long before Claude Code or anything and, uh,
is now used by a lot of, like, different teams. So this was a tool that was inspiration.
For the project that we are going to create.
For this, we are going to use GitHub Toolkit.
Now, if you notice, GitHub Toolkit is from LangChain community.
And LangChain community is deprecated.
Right? But we are going to use GitHub toolkit to develop this.
The rationale behind it is, I want to show you.
Migration as well. I'll show you how we can migrate this project.
Even after LangChain communities deprecated, so here.
In today's lecture, we are going to use Langchain community.
But in the coming lectures.
Let's say after the MCP lecture.
I'll show you how you can migrate this particular project.
To the latest specification that LangChain has provided for migrating from LangChain community.
Okay, so we are going to learn that as well. This is an essential skill because you will face this a lot.
Everybody's trying to find out the best way to build AI.
And if we are able to do that, if you are able to do migrations, it is a great skill to have.
So you can go to this particular.
URL and you can clone this repository for the time being.
clone this particular repository.
Do not open it right now, but just keep it tuned somewhere.
Okay. Langchain community is a package by Langchain that was created to provide all these kind of integrations.
But now, recently.
If you go to
LangChain.
If you see this particular issue in LangChain Community Github, you will see that.
They have archived this repository, which means that they will not develop anything.
And, uh, this will be sunset.
Okay.
No, clone, I mean.
You can either just download the zip file, or you can copy this.
You can copy this URL,
Open a terminal.
And write the following command.
Git.
Clone, paste the URL, okay?
Run this command.
Is it visible to all?
Yeah, just do this.
Give me a thumbs up once you have cloned it.
Great. Cool.
Now, let me show you. For this, we need to build a GitHub application.
Okay, because our agent is going to interact through this GitHub application.
You can consider the backend as, like, the
that our agent that we're going to build is the backend of this GitHub application that we are creating.
So, go to Settings.
You can click on your profile pic.
Go to Settings. Let me zoom out.
A little bit. Alright, so this is my profile. I went to settings.
In the settings,
You need to go to
Developer settings, ok.
Click on this developer setting.
Yeah, if you are able to follow until here, give me a thumbs up.
I just want to ensure that everybody is following it.
So Danbai go a little bit slow, maybe
All right. Bharat.
Pujan, you just need to click on my profile, like, click on your profile pic in GitHub, just go to GitHub.
Yes, I mean, you can, you can clone this repository in any working directory that you have.
Any directory.
Okay, we are going to build our application in that repository.
Cloning is not related to this, cloning is just to save the code in your system.
Go to github.com.
Go to github.com, click on your
Face icon. Just click on your profile.
You will find the settings.
Go to Settings.
Okay, and after going to settings.
Scroll down, you will find this Developer Settings. Go here.
Okay, yeah, a better way is
Thank you, Rakesh, for doing this.
A better way is just click on this URL.
In Zoom, just click on this URL.
Okay, you all should see something like this.
You may not see an application skill, uh, application screen like this.
Give me a thumbs up once you are here.
Putin, Bharat,
Yeah, you should not have any apps.
Okay, you should not have any apps.
This is something I had created earlier.
Alright, I see everybody's here.
Okay, cool.
Now, we can click on this new GitHub app.
Let's click on this new GitHub app.
Okay, once we are here.
You can open up this PDF.
You have this PDF with you, right?
Ashish, by just share this PDF with you.
You open up the PDF, you will see what all things you need to do.
Each and every step is mentioned here in this PDF, ok.
We are going to follow these steps together.
This is a housekeeping job that we are doing.
For setting up our GitHub application.
We will build agents after this particular setup is done.
Everybody with me?
We all know what to do.
Yeah? Cool. Great.
So, I'm going to name my application.
Multi-agent.
app.
And the homepage URL.
Could be my GitHub profile, so.
GitHub.
my GitHub URL.
I'm going to paste my GitHub profile URL in my
Home page URL.
Okay?
Once this is done,
I can scroll down.
Webhook is active here.
Okay, you will see that webhook is active. You need to uncheck this.
Once you inject this, this requirement will be gone.
We are not creating any webhooks.
This is done.
Okay. I can select this as well. I don't need to expire anything.
So just unselect this.
And then we can go to
Repository permissions.
So let's go to repository permissions.
Those of you who have done this, just it's okay, just look at it.
Okay. And in repository permissions, I will find out a few things. I will find out.
Contents, so you can see contents.
In content, I will write.
Read and write access. Do you know why?
Why do we need to provide read and
right access. I want to make this session really interactive, okay? Just tell me.
Anybody who knows why are we making it read and write?
Content is everything in your repository, the files that you push, all of those things.
Okay? Yasmin, I'm going slow. You can…
See this PDF okay you can just
go through this PDF one by one.
Alright, I'm with you guys, I'm waiting for you guys, don't worry, I'll not, I'll not rush.
I'll only move forward when you are
Giving me a thumbs up, acknowledging that you have completed the step, ok, don't worry.
So, in contents,
Again, I will repeat myself.
Go to permissions.
Click here.
You will see this scroll down.
Just go to Content,
And in content, you select read and write.
We are providing read and write access of our repository.
to our agent, because we want the agent.
To be able to change files that are present in my repository, that is how the agent will be able to contribute.
Okay, so.
We provided read and write permission to our agent.
And then I want you to find issues.
Because we want the agent to read issues, to solve issues.
We want the agent to…
Update issues, triage issues.
So, here as well, I'm going to provide it.
Read and write access.
Alright, so this application can, can interact with the content, it can also interact with the issues.
It can read and write issues.
Next thing that we can do is
pull request, okay? Go to pull request, just scroll down, you will find pull request.
In pull request as well, let's see what is mentioned in our file. In our file.
We are saying the agent should be able to
Read and write the pull request, right? I'm following this, this document, folks. I'm following this document, so
Read and write.
pull request, okay? I can do all of this out of the memory.
But we have provided this, I'm asking you to follow this step by step. Everything is mentioned here.
The URL I added is my profile. Supreet, you can add your GitHub profile as the URL.
Okay?
Then metadata, we need to
Set as read-only, it is, it is something pre-built, okay, so if I go to metadata, I won't be able to edit it, you see? Yeah, it is mandatory, it is read-only.
Just ensure all of these things are done, so.
Can you list what all things we changed?
We changed content.
Read and write we changed.
issues, read and write.
We chased pull request to
Read and write. All right, this is what we
need to do after doing this, our agent will be able to access all of this.
And it will be able to run it.
So now I can create my GitHub app.
Just click on this Create GitHub app. After scrolling down, you will find this option, just
Create GitHub app, ok.
You can see my name is already taken, so you need to come up with a unique name.
Alright, you can see my app has been created.
And I also have this app ID. You can see this app ID, everyone.
You need to copy this app ID.
Okay, all of you need to copy this app ID.
For those of you asking step 6,
Let me complete step 3, 4, 5.
Yeah, let me complete 3, 4, 5.
Why are you so excited? I know everybody wants to build a GitHub agent.
Here, we see a new toy, we get excited.
Just have patience. We are going to do it.
Okay.
0.6 in step 2, let's see what it is.
Yeah, we are going to do this. Just wait, have patience, have patience.
If you are, if you are, if you are
Receiving this error saying name is resolved, it means that you have to come up with a unique name.
So folks, all of these
App names are like Instagram IDs.
You cannot have same Instagram IDs, right?
So, you have to come up with a new Instagram id.
That's why, that's how.
Yeah?
All right, folks.
Let me know once you have done this, once you have created the application, you should see a screen like this.
I'm reducing it because it's too big for my eyes.
You need to copy the app ID, ok.
Copy it and…
We also need to…
Generate a new private key.
So, we can generate a new private key, just
Give me a second.
Click on Generate New Private Key, it will download this private key.
In your repository, ok.
Uh, in your downloads folder.
We need to copy it to our repository.
The staff patients, this is done.
You can…
Now…
Let's look what all things are also there.
After creating the GitHub, after creating the private key.
We are all ready.
Now we can do the select repository thing. So, now we can go to install app.
Okay, go to install app.
Click on this install app.
And here, instead of all repositories.
Click on only select repositories. I think there was some issue with the document. It should not be in the step 2. It should be in this particular step.
So, install, only click on select repositories.
It should be all repositories by default.
Click on only select repositories.
And let me see which repository I can choose.
You can choose anyone, by the way.
I'm going to choose…
Let's say I'm going to choose this…
Okay, I created this once for…
Teaching people get?
Okay, now you can click on install. After you have selected repository, I have selected one get practice repository. You can click on install.
Okay, so let's click on install. This will install it.
Here. So, folks, those of you who could not follow, go to developer settings.
Go to app that you just created, so I created this multi-agent app, Sid.
You will see this option here, install app.
Okay, click on this install app, you will see your ID.
Just install that app there.
Install that app there.
Once you install the app, you will see this.
All repositories, only select repositories.
Okay, you need to click on this only select repository radio button.
Once you click on this, only select repository radio button.
You will see this option of select repositories. When you click, you will see the repositories that you can select.
If you do not have any repository in your GitHub account,
You won't see any repositories.
Okay, if you, that's why I said, that's why I gave the 15 minute break.
That go create a
Some demo repository.
Okay. When you click here, you should see that demo repository here. Just
Select that demo repository that I asked you to create in the break.
Okay, give me a thumbs up once you are done.
Sanjeev, Ankit,
Aditya, Abhishek.
Give me a thumbs up if you're done.
Alright? Okay.
All of you have downloaded the private key as well, the .pem file got downloaded. Check your download folder if .pem file got downloaded.
Can you guys check?
got downloaded for everybody.
Yeah, danger zone will always be there, ok. See, I am also getting danger zone.
It only means that you can uninstall or suspend this application.
Don't worry about it.
Okay.
Alright folks, so all the setup that we had to make on GitHub is completed successfully.
Anybody who has not
Who was not able to do this?
Write in the text.
Krishna or Ashish Pai will try to guide you.
Okay?
Yeah, danger zone is a default… see, danger zone simply means that
Be careful while using these options.
Okay? Because these options can…
Uh, delete or suspend your…
Code. So some of you did not download
Let me go back.
Go to General, go to General.
Scroll down…
When you scroll down,
You will see this private keys option.
Okay, give me a thumbs up once you reach here, once you see this private keys option.
Give me a thumbs up.
Fujian, anybody who has
Yeah?
Just click on this Generate Private Key option.
You will see that some private key.
will get downloaded in some folder.
Alright, private keys downloaded.
We should be ready now. I'm stopping to share my screen because I need to add the private key.
It is a secret. So, let me add those things.
In a while, you also add them in the folder.
Follow the, ah.
Directions here, ok, here it is written in which folder you need to add it.
Just add it in.
In that folder, ok.
So, let me start.
Stop sharing the screen, so whatever repository I asked you to download, right, I asked you to clone a repository, right?
Just open that repository in anti-gravity.
Or VS Code, or any other code editor that you have, just open that repository.
Akotam, no issues.
Uh, you still have the file.
You can just watch for the time being, Gautam.
And, uh…
Like…
Try to set it up, it is not very difficult. I've explained each of the steps. Watch the recording and do it.
in hands-on, okay? If you face any issues, just reach out on Discord.
Alright folks, I'm stopping to share my screen. Please open up.
The repository that you cloned.
Not the one that you created, but the one that I sent you, ok.
Let me send that link again.
So…
GitHub.
GitHub agent.
Just this repository.
Open it.
In your…
Yeah, open, open this, open this repository.
In your ID.
Okay.
I'm just doing some…
Like, I'm just copying the private key that I downloaded.
Give me a second to just copy-paste it.
Okay, my private key is loaded.
I think all my…
Environment files are ready.
I just need to
So, whatever…
app ID that you got,
You need to copy paste that app ID as well.
In your GitHub env file.
Okay, if any of you ask, ask me what, like, give me your .env file, I'll just get very angry, ok, so don't ask me.
Uh…
Let's add this.
Right? I've seen people, they asked me my .env file.
So, yeah.
All right.
Okay, so everybody has opened up their
ENV file.
Yeah?
Alright, let me share my screen and get started.
with code explanation.
Alright folks, so I think somebody was really excited to work on IDE. I don't remember the name, I think it was Vinod, Vivek, something.
Who was very excited.
To work on ID.
I saw a question every day.
All right.
All right. So see, I have shared this sample.env file with all of you.
Take this, copy it in a .env file. You need to create it using this icon.
Okay, if you are in VS Code, if you are in anti-gravity, you can use the side icon to create this .env.
File, just copy paste all of these things.
Here you need to paste the app ID.
Okay, what is the app ID?
When you open up Github, you will see this app ID here.
Alright, do you see this app ID here?
Just paste, copy and paste this app ID.
In your .env, okay? I'm just… I'm showing it to you in sample.env, but you need to paste it in .env.
In this .env.
Paste it here. GitHub app private.
You do not need to paste the content of private key here, but
You need to copy-paste the private key in this resource folder. You need to create a resource folder.
or any folder here.
And then you click on…
Copy relative path, okay? Copy relative path, whatever path is present.
You need to paste that path here.
So the name of my
file PEM file.
is my github key.m.
And it is in the resources folder of my agent.
Uh, working directory, so just paste that here.
Oh, Ringanathan, you guys are re-baiting me now.
Alright, I'm very calm, okay, I wouldn't get angry.
So yeah, Pradeep, you won't see .env file in the repo, you need to create your own .env file. So just click on this icon.
Okay, click on this icon and create .env file.
I'm sorry, which repo link we need to give?
Is it the one we created?
It's not the one you created, it's the one that I shared.
I shared it in the link.
Can… can anybody please help Umesh?
Umesh, you can share the screenshot of where you're stuck.
Uh, people will try to help you out.
Okay, don't worry, Umesh. It's okay, you can.
Continue by watching the recording as well.
Just follow these steps here.
Okay, so everybody.
paste the .pem file in a new resource folder that you create. You can create a new folder by clicking here.
Paste the PM file here and copy the path of it here.
Paste the GitHub ID, I have the Github ID.
So I just pasted the GitHub ID, right?
Just paste the GitHub ID in your .env.
And then add your Grok API key as well.
Your .env should look like this with the Grok API key.
Give me a thumbs up once all of you are done until here.
All right. Great. Okay, Venkat is doing.
I want to see some spirit of collaboration, folks. Just help out people who are not able to do it themselves.
Uh, folks, whoever is stuck, ask in the chat.
Everybody who is ahead of them, try to help them out, ok.
Because now the setup is done. Now I'm just going to explain code.
Yeah, don't worry, Bharat, no issues.
Ashish Bhayakrishnai, please try to help them out. You can share the screenshot of wherever you are stuck at.
They'll try to help you out.
Okay, let, let me give a
Yeah, let me give a 5-minute timer for everybody.
To get on the same page.
If you are done until here, then we can focus on the code part, okay? Setup is complete once.
We are done with filling up the environment variable and you are, you have set up the API key.
I see many people are still struggling, so let me give you all 5 minutes to do that.
Ashish Vai, can you please start a timer for 5 minutes?
Yeah, and everybody else, please try to help them out.
Yeah, no need of resource folder.
I created the resource folder because
I follow, like, I try to follow good practices.
Having a specific folder for all of these kind of resources is a good practice.
Okay, you don't have to worry about searching where everything is.
If you, you can keep it as it is in anywhere in the repo.
But it won't look tidy, okay? I like to keep things tidy. That's why I created a resource folder.
I like to teach it to others as well, that please keep your report ID as if
The next person who is going to develop on that code is a psychopathic serial killer.
Okay, you should have this in mind, that
Whichever application you develop.
Whoever is going to inherit that code from you.
Is a psychopathic serial killer.
And they will come for you if you have made any mistakes there, okay? That's how you should keep your repositories.
Keep it very clean and tidy.
Ashishbhai, can we start our 5-minute timer, please?
Yes, just give me a minute.
folks get on the same page.
Okay, 4 minute timers, Ashish Bhai.
Uh, no, this should be the repo that you created. For me, it is.
Uh, so, the GitHub repository in the environment variable.
Should be the repository that you created, the repository that you selected. Let me update it in my code as well.
Okay, it should be the repository that you have selected.
While installing the application.
Wherever you have installed the application, only that repo you can.
All right.
So, I have selected the git practice one.
I'm adding that.
Okay, folks, whichever repository you have created, you need to add that in your
Get practice. Let me send you, uh…
Template for your .env.
So that…
Okay, folks, see, I have mentioned in the chat.
In GitHub app ID, just put your GitHub app ID.
As GitHub app private key, put the path of your dot PEM file wherever you have downloaded that PEM file.
Add the path of that PM file.
In your GitHub repository, you can add the repository that you selected to install.
Okay, whichever repository you selected to install, just select that.
Azure Grok API key.
Just select your Grok API key.
Okay, everybody clear? Give me a thumbs up if most of you who get stuck are dumped.
People who are already done do not give a thumbs up. Those people who were stuck.
And they are done, just give me a thumbs up.
And folks, it, uh…
I'm sorry if others are…
Waiting because of other people.
Let's be collaborative, let's ensure that everybody is able to follow everybody. All of our classmates are.
Doing well, okay?
Done, I see most people are done.
Yeah, Ringanathan, I said, right, in the Github repo, just
Let me…
Whatever repo you selected while installing, whatever new repo you have created, add that.
Alright, I see that most people are done.
Okay, Bharat, your app is installed. You don't need to do anything there.
Bharat.
Your app is installed already, you have saved it.
Okay, it seems that you have already saved it.
So, in the .env file.
Bharat, you can add this Bharat Vamsi 14 slash
Multi-agent. This is what you can add in your
.env file, ok, in Github repository.
Keep.
Bharat, are you done?
All right, Vamsi.
Yeah, just ignore the danger zone.
Awesome, awesome, everybody's done.
We can start now.
Alright, our .env file is ready. Now let's look at the code.
Okay, folks, excited?
We are going to build our GitHub agent now.
And Asher, you can stop sharing your screen.
I am opening up my anti-gravity.
So, this is the repository that I asked you to clone.
This is the first.
I think in IDE application that we are building, so we are building this application in IDE.
Because this cannot be done on Google collab.
Can be done, but it's better to work on IDE.
Let me walk you through the code here.
So, this typical project
structure that you see.
is the structure of a UV project.
Okay, whenever you do UV init, you will get
All of these files, you will get this TOML file, you will get this uvlock file.
You will have a main.py, you will have a Python version, a gitignore, and a .venv.
I have installed many packages here, so we have LangChain, we have Langchain community, we have LangChain Core, we have LangChain Grok.
Landgraph, PyGitHub, and tick token.
Why buy GitHub? PyGitHub because
Lansing Community.
uses this GitHub integration with the help of PyGithub.
package. So we have PyGitHub.
And this is the TOML file. This toml file.
Tells our Python environment what all files we need to install.
Okay, so all of you.
can click on Control.
And tilde sign.
How many of you know tilde? It is the wave icon.
At the… it is closer to 1, okay? Just click on that.
You will see that a terminal gets opened up.
Here, open your, open up your terminal.
Here you can run this command called
U V.
SYNC Sync.
Okay, to run this uv sync command.
Once you do this,
All your packages will be installed.
And you will see a dot venv file created.
And a UV.log file created.
Okay. Give me a thumbs up once you are done with this.
UV is not recognized, ok, so you have not installed UV. If you have not installed UV,
For those of you who have not installed UV.
Just go to
Google.
UV.
Install which OS do you use? I use Windows so
Windows. Just search for this. You will see this UV installation doc.
Go here, choose your OS, and install it.
Okay, uh, Syed, I would recommend not to use pip install UV.
Because then the UV environment is associated with your tip environment, I would rather use it.
Independently.
So that it is not associated with…
Any Python version or any specific
Uh, pip file that I have.
So those of you who have not installed UV.
Just install it.
It is a package manager. UV is a package manager.
So UV is just like
Maven, just like Gradle, just like NPM.
Okay, either of those, whichever is familiar to you.
So download UV package manager. Give me a thumbs up once you're done.
With syncing your repository.
Uh, you can use Renganathan, you can use PIP if you are comfortable with PIP.
Kavi Kavi, you need to check if you are…
You need to check the path if you are in the correct path, ok.
GitHub.agent contains a pyproject.toml.
Si vasis, you as well.
Check if you are in pyproject.toml.
Yeah, you need to open this GitHub agent repo, folks, this cloned repo.
The link that I shared.
Ran UV.
sync there, okay? All right. I see most of you are done. Those of you who are not done, you will get help from your peers in the chat.
Or you can watch the recording later on.
So, once we have done this, you will see .venv.uv.log.
Just select, just open up the command line again.
Type dot Venv.
Script tab.
Activate tab.
If you are in Windows, you should see this.
Those who are not in Windows, you can use the source command. So, right, source.
And then this, this particular path.
And then press enter. Okay.
Once you do this, something has changed. Can anybody recognize what has changed?
Anybody? Can you recognize what has changed?
Yeah, virtual environment is activated, ok.
So you can see this particular line here, my virtual environment is activated.
I can clear this up. Now my repository is ready.
For work. So I can close my terminal again by clicking on control tilde.
Terminal is closed. Let me walk you through the project structure.
So, all the code in my project lives in this SRC.
Nitesh, can you just Google?
Activate virtual environment? Yeah, can you just Google? Guys, whoever is in Linux, macOS,
Just Google, activate virtual environment.
In Mac, in Ubuntu, whatever you was.
Yeah, yeah, I think source main activate is the one.
Okay, so go to SRC.
In SRC, I have implemented two different packages.
One package is where I have implemented my agent.
There is another package where I've implemented my workflow.
I'm not going to run the workflow, just going to show it to you.
And then we will see how we have implemented the
Agent package. Okay, so let me open up main.py. You do not need to write any code here. I've implemented everything for you.
But you need to have an in-depth understanding of this code, ok.
Sai Shridan, thank you so much for doing this.
Okay, I see great community spirit today. I'm really happy.
Thank you for doing this.
You can find all the commands relevant to whatever terminal you're using.
Okay?
All right, everybody with me?
Everybody has all the setup now.
Can you follow the code? Can we begin?
Awesome. I see only 3?
Alright, awesome.
Great. Let's…
Understand the whole code.
Soul.
What is the first thing that I need to create for my workflow?
I'm creating a stateful workflow.
What is the first thing that I need to do?
Note state exactly.
I need to define the state.
On which the workflow will
Process. So
I am creating a simple release note generator here, ok.
Release node generation should not require any agents.
As long as the project is not very complicated.
It can be a simple workflow which checks what all commits happened before, after the previous release.
and create a release note for all of those.
New features that were added in those commits.
Okay, that is all.
That happens when you write a release note, right?
So, to automate that process.
We create a state where we write release info.
We have a state for PRN commit, which is a list of string.
And we add a state parameter called
release notes, which is a string.
So, this is what my workflow will try to populate.
Then, I need to do a few housekeeping things.
I need to instantiate my LLM.
which is Chad Grok. I need to create this GitHub API wrapper, okay?
How, how do you know this? How?
Do you know what to do? Go to the documentation, this is what you need to do.
Okay, in the documentation you will see.
You need to create this GitHub API wrapper, then you need to create this toolkit.
Okay, just follow whatever is present inside the documentation.
I've done the same, I have instantiated a
GitHub API wrapper. Now, using the instance of this GitHub API wrapper.
I've taken it, I have given it to this.
From the GitHub API wrapper.
Method of this GitHub
Toolkit.
This will provide me access to all the tools.
That can be used to interact with GitHub.
You remember, right, agent can perform real-world actions.
So, changing anything on GitHub is a real-world action.
For that, for performing real-world action, what do we need?
Anybody in the chat? What do we need?
perform real-world action.
Tools, exactly, right.
So?
This tool is nothing but a wrapper around the GitHub API.
GitHub provides a developer API.
LangChain folks took that developer API.
And wrapped it in a function.
Annotated it with other tools provided.
this to you as an integration.
Okay, so.
We get access to all of these tools.
And then.
I am creating a map of
tools. How am I creating a map of tools?
The map is a simple dictionary.
Where the tool name is the key.
And the tool itself is the value.
Okay, that is what I have done in this particular line.
And…
Then I have created all of these nodes. You can see what these are.
These are simple Python functions.
Yeah, these are simple Python functions.
So I have created a Python function that can collect all PRN commits.
Using the list pull request tool.
Okay, it is just running the GitHub running.
By taking GitHub repo as a parameter.
So, it is collecting all the PRN commits then.
It is getting all the previous releases, it is just to check.
Which release was the last release?
Which release is the release for which I will be writing some.
Uh, release notes.
And then I can take all of these Python functions. How do I convert these Python functions into my
Nodes. Anybody in the chat? Yesterday you learned it, right? And Srinha taught it really well.
So how can we convert these Python functions into
Notes, my graph nodes.
Exactly, add node, right? So I create a graph instance where I will pass in my state.
So this is the state that will be transferred between all my nodes.
I add it here, I instantiate my graph.
And in the graph, I use the add node method.
To give a name of my node and the actual executor of that node, ok.
So function is the executor of that node.
Whatever operation will be executed in that node should be written in this function.
So I have provided this. This function will release a state that will go to the next node, next node, next node, and so on.
Now, tell me, we have added all of these three nodes. Are these nodes connected with each other right now?
Give me a thumbs up if you think it is connected, give me a thumbs down if it is not, not yet, yeah, I see.
Yes, so how can we connect it?
We can, we need edges, exactly, right, so.
Graph.addH.
We always start with the start node, ok.
This is a default node that is provided by
We always start with the start node.
Then, whatever first node that needs to be executed will come here.
After that, where should we go from this node to this node? So, this is a sequential graph.
Okay, how many of you think this is a sequential graph?
Yeah, everybody? Great.
I'm really happy to see that all of you are able to follow up.
So this is a sequential graph where
Each node will be getting called one after the other.
Exactly, if there are no conditional edges, then it means that it is a sequential graph.
But what if…
After this particular
After calling getReleaseNode.
I again added a new edge.
Where from get release node, I'm going back to get PR node.
And then going to end. There will be a cycle, right?
Yeah?
All right.
Okay, so we can do graph.compile.
After doing graph.compile, my
workflow is ready, I can invoke it, and my release tools will be generated.
Okay? This was a simple workflow.
Now, using the same principles, we are going to create our agent.
Let us go to source.
Let us go to agents. And so you all understand, right, how tools can be used.
Inside a workflow, how actual like GitHub LangChain tools can be used inside a workflow.
Now, if in any of these workflow,
If in any of these workflow,
I'll tell you one thing. If in any of these workflows.
Let's say this collect PR commit.
If I make it an agent.
If I make it an agent,
Wrap it up in a function.
Okay? If in this function, instead of calling this tool.
I call an agent.
that does this get PR?
Uh, with me, by invoking.
A bunch of tools.
And I add this function, this parent function where my agent is running.
As a node,
What will you call this kind of a workflow?
No, not, there is single agent.
In this workflow.
Yeah, it will be an agentic workflow, ok, it will be an agentic workflow.
No subgraph, nothing, no.
It will be an agentic workflow for folks.
Only one node has an agent that is running, okay? If there is only one node where an agent is running, it is going to be called an agentic workflow.
Yeah? Awesome.
So, now you know all the building blocks. Do you think, how many of you think that you can confidently build
An agentic system now, give me a thumbs up.
With some practice, obviously.
Now, all the required knowledge is with you.
Yeah? Okay.
All of you who have given me a thumbs up.
Next week, I need to see something that you have built, ok.
You need to share it on Discord.
I don't know what it is. Build something, come up with an idea.
I will give two people the stage to speak about it.
Okay, in the end, after the lecture, I'll, I'll
Uh, give 2 people the stage to speak about it.
Let's see who does it.
Okay. Awesome.
Now, let's go to agents.
And in agents.
You can see I have a utils file.
And I have a graph.py file.
Okay?
Let's go through it one by one. In this graph.py file, I'm not really using any
Uh, land graph.
Lecting.
I've used simple approach, but you can use LandGraph here as well.
I will leave it up to you. I want you guys to experiment.
So let's go through utils.py first.
You see that
When we get access to the GitHub tools that we have.
It is written like this, get issues.
Yeah, get issue.
Comment on issues.
Do you think this is programming friendly?
Do you think this is agentic friendly?
This is tool friendly for our LLM.
This kind of name.
No, why? Because our agents are trained.
In such a way that they consider tools as some kind of functions.
Yeah, so there cannot be a space, there cannot be all of this.
They need to look like this, like function names.
So, we need to change the name of all of these tools.
We need to rename these tools.
from something that is human-friendly.
To something that is AI friendly.
That is why I've written this utils.py.
Here, I have written a simple function which is rename tool.
And this is just going to
Uh, access the tool name.
And update it, ok, from the tool name mapping, we created this tool name mapping, remember, ok.
So I have done that.
This will rename all the tools.
With this mapping.
With this mapping, ok.
So get issues will be renamed to get issues.
GetIsue will be renamed to getissue, and so on.
This utility function will do that for me.
Then, I have written functions to fetch relevant tools based on the task.
So…
issue triage will come here. So, all the issue tools will come.
Will be returned just by calling this function.
So, I want to keep my code clean, right? So these are all the utility functions.
If I have to perform tool review,
I should not think while developing my agent, which tools should I call? So I've created this utility function that will only return me the bunch of tools.
that are required for code review.
Okay?
So, do you need… do you need to use the right right file tool?
For code review, give me a thumbs up.
If you need, no, right?
Yeah, you do not need.
Uh, right tool for code review.
You only need the read tools, ok, you need search tool, you need read tool, all of these.
So I've added only those tools.
So, what is the principle I'm following here?
Can anybody with a good amount of programming experience can tell me?
Which particular principle I'm following here?
Exactly, leased access, ok.
Principle of least privileges.
Remember it, it should not only be for your users.
It should also be for your agents.
Principle of least privileges.
It should be for your agents as well.
So, only provide the list of tools that they require.
Follow this pattern. This is really useful. I've created.
Such kind of helper functions for all of these.
And then in my graph.py.
Let's see how we are building agent.
Everybody with me, give me a thumbs up if you have understood so far.
Just give me a thumbs up if you have understood so far. If you're all following up.
It's all making sense.
Awesome. All right, great.
Okay, folks.
Uh, Ravindra, can you ask any specific question?
Yes, the two names are from GitHub.
The tool names are from GitHub. I will tell you how I have defined tools, everything, just give me a second.
Okay? That utility function.
was able to help us rename tools and fetch all the tools.
But it required a list of all the tools, okay?
That is something that it always requires.
So, let's see. Here as well, we have followed the same steps.
I have…
Instantiated my LLM.
After instantiating my LLM,
I've created a GitHub API wrapper.
From this GitHub API wrapper.
I got this GitHub toolkit.
Okay? And this toolkit contains all the tools.
If I call this get tool function, I will get those tools.
So, I am getting a list of all those tools.
I am iterating through the list.
And I'm using this renameTool function. Anybody knows, remembers this renameTool function?
Here, I'm using this renameTool function to rename
The tools from this default name, which is human readable.
To this.
AI native name, okay.
So, after running this, all my tool names will be updated to the mapping that we saw.
in utils.py.
We can now create our agent.
So I'm starting by creating our sub-agents.
I have used this convention of using an underscore.
Before my sub-agents, ok.
This is a popular.
Convention for defining subagents.
But it is not necessary, ok.
It will make no difference if I remove this.
It will still be a sub-agent, ok, on its own.
So, but it is a good practice.
To keep it this way, because it helps.
Any, it helps the psychopathic serial killer.
programmer who is going to
take this over after me.
That, this is a sub-agent, okay?
So, just keep it in mind, right?
Good code.
Just make that difference clear, okay?
So define it like this.
The process of defining a sub-agent is same.
Use create agent function.
Passing your model.
Passing the tools that you have.
Name your agent, so I am naming it document agent.
And then provide a system prompt.
Regarding a very specialized task that it needs to do.
Okay. So, this is documentation subagent, you can go through it.
We similarly also have release node subagent.
Okay? This will have access to all the release node tools.
Then we have issue agent.
The issue agent will have access to this.
Issue tools, so how am I getting access to these tools?
I have defined my helper function.
So that's why this looks really clean, right? The code looks really clean.
You should keep it this way.
What am I passing here as tools?
The list of all the tools.
I'm passing the list of all the tools.
Into my helper function. My helper function is picking the tools.
And giving least privilege.
For whatever task it is supposed to do.
So, system prompt.
I'll tell you, I'll tell you, Karthik.
Karthik is asking, how did I decide the system prompt for each of these?
There are a few things that you need to keep in mind while designing a system prompt.
You should understand that the purpose of system prompt is to giving your agent a role.
So that should be the first thing.
You are a code review agent, you are an issue management agent. You are a release note agent.
You are a documentation agent.
After this, after you have given them a role.
You need to give them the task that they are supposed to do, okay?
So there is a method, it is called craft.
C-R-A-F-T.
Oh, I'm typing in my VS Code. Sorry. I was typing it in chat.
C-R-A-F-D.
You can you can Google what is craft prompt strategy.
Okay? C is for context.
R is for role, A is for action.
F is for format, T is for
Um…
I think T is for task.
T is for task.
So just I need to provide them a role.
After that, I need to give them some tasks that they need to do.
I need to specify what actions they can perform. So here it is the
tools that they can… they have access to, ok.
That's how you can design a great system prompt.
Alright, so all my, I have a few.
Agents here.
And then I've created a enum for my agent names, ok, I've created an enum for my agent names.
I am just…
Taking all of these sub-agents.
All of these sub-agents.
I am…
Encapsulating these sub-agents in separate functions.
So, these are functions where
I'm just going to call this agent, ok.
And whatever they return.
I am converting them, I'm converting their response into a tool message.
Can you guys tell me what have I done here?
In this function, I'll explain it, but I want you to guess.
Yeah, context, role,
Action format and tone.
Yes.
All right. So folks, anybody would tell me what I've done here.
This is a very
Like, you have seen this.
You have seen this multiple times until now.
Exactly, exactly. So I've converted Sunil.
Everybody, let's clap for Sunil, ok, he guessed it right.
So, what we have done here is,
We have wrapped our agent in a function.
That we have annotated as a tool.
You all can see where this is going, how we are converting, how we are creating a multi-agent system, right?
This is a supervisor pattern that we are using.
In the supervisor pattern.
Each agent acts like a tool.
Okay, so.
We did this for the documentation agent, we added some descriptions here.
We added the name.
Okay, by the way, if you are skipping
Any docstring, you can add description like this.
In this at the rate tool, ok.
If I were a good developer, if I had written docstring here, I would not have to do this.
So?
And remember that multi-agent communication happens through these commands.
So, your sub-agent should return this tool message.
Okay, so whatever result you want to fetch, you cannot print everything, right? You cannot print everything from the result.
Because that, what will, what will happen if I, if I
Send the whole result.
If I return the whole result here, what will happen?
Anyone?
Context will blow up, exactly.
Your manager does not need to know each and every step that you followed. Your manager only needs to know whether or not the task was completed well or not.
Okay? Exactly. So, we are only checking the last message which is always the conclusion message.
We are only wrapping it up as a tool message and sending as a command.
To the supervisor agent. Okay. In short, so this is context management that we have done.
When we teach you context engineering, we'll come back to all of these.
Okay, so, so these are the
Nitty gritties, these are the
Underlying principles that you need to.
Understand. So, command is a way through which you can.
Do agent-to-agent communication in LangChain.
Okay, if you need to send any message to any agent, you can use command.
not only agent to agent, but even from a tool,
from any middleware, if you want to send it to agent, if you want to send it to anyone.
to Langchain or line graphs, you can use this command.
We'll talk about it more, ok, we'll talk about this command thing more.
If you want, I can share the documentation of this command as well.
But this is usually used.
I think you must have…
seen this already. I think you should yesterday in Human in the loop.
You must have used this command.
Whenever you want to inject any message.
Whenever you want to inject any new message.
into an LLM pipeline or
an agent, you use this command.
In LangChain and LandGraph, ok.
So, in this command, I'm passing tool message, the tool that has executed right now.
What is the tool? The tool is a
Documentation agent.
No, response should be a tool message.
Because this agent is acting like a tool.
For my supervisor agent.
Srinivas, you understood?
This agent is acting like a tool for my supervisor agent.
So whatever I did for documentation agent, I need to do similar things for all my sub-agent.
So for my release node agent.
For my, uh…
Issue tracker agent for my code review agent.
For all of these agents.
I did the same thing, I wrapped them up in a function.
Annotated it with at the rate tool.
And then I created my GitHub agent, which is like the main coordinator agent.
So, which pattern we have followed here?
Anyone which pattern we have followed here?
Supervisors. Exactly. Coordinator or supervisor.
It is not hierarchical.
These agents do not have any sub-agent, right?
So, it is not hierarchical, it is supervisor.
So, again, use create agent function.
LLM tools were
Each tool is an LLM.
Is an agent.
And then I added a main system prompt where I
Delegated the task.
And then I can simply ask it.
To create a documentation and raise a PR for it.
So you can see it is doing multiple tasks, ok, it is doing a complex task.
It has to create documentation, so…
The first thing will go to documentation agent.
Once the documentation is generated,
It will go to the PR agent to raise a PR.
Okay, this is a multi-step process.
By the way, folks, to perform tasks like this,
You need better models. We are using GPT-OSS, which is a 120B parameter model.
Okay, it is a very simple model.
So, you may face issues in the first run, second run.
But if it fails, try it multiple times, it should work.
All of you with me, all of you understood how we implemented a multi-agent system.
Anurag, that is what is happening right now.
Supervisor is dynamically
executing agents.
supervisor decides the sequence on the go.
That is why it is agentic in nature, right? We have not programmed the sequence.
The agent will program its own sequence.
Based on the task that it has.
It has been assigned.
Yes, Gautam, if you have Claude API, you can substitute this model.
In fact, I will suggest you use your own model. This is a very basic GitHub agent.
build a very complex one.
We, we, one of the students from cohort 1.
Srini, he built a really complicated GitHub agent. He took this project as a base.
He added a bunch of features, added a lot of guardrails and everything, and he built.
create agent. So you can also try to do that.
We have given tools and tasks, agent decides what to do when.
Exactly.
Workflow is desired by agent.
Should we… yeah, yeah, Ameh, we will run this.
Just let me answer a few questions.
Here, we have defined the sub-agent supervisor as picking one of them. I mean, even.
Creating subagents we done? No, create… it is not creating sub-agents on the fly, Anurag.
We have defined it, like we have defined the agents that
can be used, it is not creating any agent on the fly.
Yes, yes, Sanjeev. So the tool list that we, the mapping that we have done here.
So this get release, get releases, these are all real tools with human readable names.
We have converted this human-readable names to AI-readable names. That's all we have done here.
Because if we keep it like this, this will be…
Uh, and really like.
not well formatted for the model to call tools.
Alright, let's run this. So, to run this.
We can…
start our virtual environment, which should already be present here.
And you can write UV run
And wherever this is, so this is in
SRC?
Agents.
Graph.py.
All right, you see this command folks.
UV run src agentsgraph.py.
Click on this, it should run, fingers crossed.
Let's see.
Uh…
Sunset attempted relative import with no parent package.
Okay.
Let me go to CD.
SRC.
Then run.
Okay.
Folks, just give me a minute, I'll fix it and come back.
Uh, it should be something in the command itself.
Yeah, oh, sorry, yeah.
All right, I think it is written in the doc as well.
So we can use this UV run python dash m.
For some reason, it is throwing this error.
All right.
Okay, it's running now. So folks,
Use this command that people have shared in the chat.
UV run python-m src.agents.graph.
Okay, use this command to run it.
I think I've…
The package layers are very deep.
For that reason.
So, it should take some time.
To run. Meanwhile you can go to github and check the package that you added here. So where is this added? It is added in GitHub practice, right?
So let me go to this.
repository, github practice.
O see, updated now.
I did not update it.
Let's go here.
Okay, GitHub practice.
Do we have a pull request? No.
Let's see, do we have a new branch?
Add README, see, now this is, this has been updated now. I'm not doing it.
Agent is doing it.
You can see.
We can see it has added all of this.
Let's see, ok, this is executed.
So…
Let's see. Let's see.
8.
This has been executed.
And…
Earlier, there were no… like, it has created this new branch.
Feature branch 1 minute ago, add README.
It has added it, but it has not created a PR.
Don't know why it did not create a PR.
Let's try running it again.
So, folks, we are using a very basic model. If you use
Uh, complex model, you should be able to do this.
Pradeep, please add your Grok API key.
Okay.
It is not able to generate the PR.
But it should be able to…
It has created a…
Another one, add project overview right now. So, see, our agent is able to perform.
All these tasks, see here it has created this doc.
Okay, folks, share in screenshot if your agent was able to run successfully and
It was able to create these things.
Sunil, okay?
it has added for you.
Great.
Folks, whoever are, whoever is getting an error.
Try to use this command. I'm just copy pasting it.
Just run this.
Yeah, if your model is good, it should be able to add PR as well.
Oh, see, for some people it created PR.
Awesome, awesome, folks!
So congratulations, you have just built a multi-agent system.
If you are facing any issues, any errors,
You can check this out, okay?
Do this thing. If you are using anti-gravity or clod.
Just add this particular.
Just take this, ok.
Take this file.
So…
Just take this file.
Add it here.
Or you can skip adding the file, like you can upload the file itself.
And after adding the file, you just…
Scroll over whatever error you are getting like this.
Click on this chat icon. Okay, click on this chat icon.
Click on this chat icon.
And here you can write that help me fix this error.
Based on this documentation.
Just do this.
Yeah, it should create a new branch, add code, do all of those things.
If you are using a better model, it should be able to create a PR as well.
Okay?
Let's see, in our documentation tool, we have documentation tool, we have issue tool, we have code review tool.
Here we have code review tool.
I think in our documentation tool,
We should add this.
add PR as well.
So see, there is no create PR or anything.
If we add, let's say, let's, let's add this, let's add.
Create pull request.
Let's add this tool in our documentation. I think then it should be able to do this.
Yeah, let us add it.
And let's run our graph again.
I think I should get a PR now.
Yeah, because see, model is very primitive. The model that we are using is very primitive.
Okay. It will need a lot of engineering to enable the model to do this. I think we can
Uh, enhance our system prompt as well for the model.
Okay, so.
We have added code review agent or whatever, we can say that, okay, if you need to create PR, you can use code review agent to
And we have named it… we have not named it well. We should have a PR agent, or we should have something like that.
So…
I can say this this particular
Agent that we have built.
Can improve by a lot.
And I would give you all a homework to improve it.
Okay?
So…
Just find this common things.
Let's say, okay, see, after adding that PR function.
My pull request is also created.
Add README documentation.
And 1 minute ago by C.
Multi-agent app said it is a bot PR.
Alright folks.
Congratulations, we have just
created a multi-agent system, a class for all of us.
I hope you enjoyed building this.
Yeah.
Alright, so your cohort is complete.
Yeah. Code is complete in just eight sessions.
We have…
I don't know how many more.
All right.
Okay, folks.
I just added this, this function.
So in the utils,
In the utils, in this get documentation tool.
I added this create pull request function.
Okay, I just added this function.
Awesome, awesome, I see many people creating PRs. Folks, share the screenshot of whatever your agent has.
was able to achieve.
It's okay if GROK token succeeded.
Uh, we can use a better model, but
I hope all of you, all of you,
Through this session, we're able to understand the fundamental of building a multi-agent system.
How to give it access to a real-world tool?
And how to let your…
agent perform real-world actions.
Just give me a thumbs up. If you are able to follow this, if you are able to understand this really well,
Awesome, I see all of you are able to do this.
Uh, we can do a quick Slido quiz.
And after Slido quiz,
We can have some Q&A.
And I can share a few nuggets regarding building good multi-agent systems.
Okay, so these are the two things left.
Slido quiz, Q&A, and
Bit of, like, little bit of nuggets on.
designing multi-agent system.
That we gathered from our experience, from experience of
Multiple developers, multiple AI agents that we talk.
2 from Big Tech.
Uh, for many people I see that token is like exceeded.
See, there are many errors that you guys can see.
Just add the, just open your anti-gravity.
Okay? It's very simple. Just open your anti-gravity, open the downloads folder
Copy-paste this GitHub agent steps here.
The standard, ok.
You can add media or something.
So, I have my downloads folder. In the downloads folder.
Where is it?
Okay, I cannot add that media, but you can copy paste the text.
So copy paste the text,
In anti-gravity, you cannot do it, in Claude, you can.
So…
From the documentation, there are some common errors and whatever.
Copy-paste that thing.
Whatever error you are getting, select it.
Select it from your terminal right here.
Okay, let's say this is the error, select on terminal.
You will see this chart icon.
You are seeing this chat icon, everybody?
Whoever is facing error,
Can you just select it, click on the chat icon?
You should be able to see something like this.
Yasmin, can you check the repository you provided in .env?
It would have added it in that particular…
The repo itself.
Okay, so add it and ask.
Help me fix this.
Folks, just try this out.
Whoever is facing an issue, just try this out.
Yeah, and all these errors that you're talking about, we have provided you the remediation in that PDF.
You can check the common errors and the reason for that errors.
And you will be able to fix it.
Just check the documentation that we have shared.
Okay?
Are folks getting any errors, any issues? Don't worry.
We will help you in GitHub, uh, sorry, we will help you in Discord.
Is it fine? Is it fine?
Can you run it later and get help on Discord?
Would it work?
Folks, give me a thumbs up if it works. Whoever is facing
facing an issue?
I see.
Yeah, Kotesh, your agent has also worked.
Create.
Yasmin, can you check the PR? Can you check the branches? Can you check the branches?
Can you check if the agent has created any new branch in your GitHub?
It must have created a new branch where it would have added some code.
In my Github, it looks like this.
In my… so this is my GitHub repository.
You can see I have a pull request.
Okay, and the number of branches I had has increased.
From 5, it is…
This many and all of these were added right now. So, this was 7 minutes ago, the latest one.
And when I go to this branch, you can see I have a new README file.
Which has all of these.
Documentation.
Okay. If I go to my main branch, there is no documentation, no readme file.
Okay, I will do a quick recap.
I will do a quick recap now.
Karthik, yes, there is a way.
And that's what we have like many other sessions for.
So, you must be feeling right. How many of you feel like we have
Learned agentic AI now.
I don't know what all these sessions are for.
All the next sessions are for. Yeah.
I see Santosh field set.
Many people feel it, right?
We'll show you, like, that this is a very deep subject.
You will all know about how to observe these agents while they are running.
How to observe these agents, how to evaluate your
RAG pipelines, how to evaluate any agentic application that you built.
We are going to learn about context engineering, how to manage context efficiently. By the way, I have added all of these little nuggets while
Covering all of the topics already.
But in those lectures, you will see how all of this comes together.
Okay, so…
Let's wait, let's wait for it.
Today, I just want you all to party and enjoy that your agent was able to create, you know,
Take a real-world action.
Because Aditya, how did you figure out that you had to add PR to the definition?
Because I checked my code,
And I found it missing in my documentation agent.
Okay, I saw the behavior of my agent.
I read, I read this.
So, this is the trace of whatever my agent has done, right? I read the trace.
And after adding the trace.
I could figure out that, ok.
It is not getting the tool to perform that action.
So I just added it here.
So now we can apply for… no, no, hold your horses, sorrow of you.
You guys need to learn a lot.
And we'll teach you those things.
All right.
Let's… let's…
Recap everything once again.
So, we created a GitHub apps.
By going onto our developer settings.
This GitHub app is a way for us to interact with GitHub programmatically.
through the GitHub Developer APIs.
We use the LangChain GitHub integration.
Which is a LangChain package that uses GitHub Developer APIs internally.
to provide us with tools,
That can interact with.
Uh, GitHub using agents.
So, we use that toolkit.
And we did a few housekeeping tasks.
Like, we just
Renamed all the tools.
To be more AI readable.
After renaming the tools to be more AI readable.
We created helper functions.
To get only the tools that are relevant for specific tasks.
Then we created a graph.py file.
Where I…
Created.
Some sub-agents, okay, we created sub-agents using the create.
Agent function from Langchain.
Here, we passed in our LLM.
We passed in, we called the function utility function.
passed all the tools that we have access to by connecting with GitHub.
And added our system prompt, our sub-agent was ready.
Similarly, we created multiple such subagents.
After creating all of these sub-agents.
We wrapped these agents.
into a function.
And annotated that function with tool decorator to convert that function into a
Langchain tool.
After that,
We took all of these tools, which are agents on their own.
And added them to a supervisor agent with a supervisor prompt.
After doing all of this, our
Supervisor agent is ready. Our multi-agent system is ready.
And we can…
Invoke it like this. This was a supervisor pattern.
That we followed. How would you create a sequential agent?
Folks, can you tell me? How can we create a sequential agent?
Using whatever you have learned.
You have learned all the level blocks to do this.
I want to add in that, you know.
that mindset in you, that you can do.
You can rearrange the Lego blocks to achieve the result that you want.
Any idea how we can create the sequential one?
No, Poojan, yesterday's why finance was
A single agent.
Exactly. Use LangGraph linear nodes.
And each node, each node should be what?
Each node should be what?
An agent, exactly.
Okay, great.
How can you create a hierarchical pattern?
Using whatever you have learned.
How do you create a hierarchical pattern?
All of these things should seem very easy to you now.
Yeah, folks. Using subgraph one way.
Yeah, subgraph is one way. Another way is…
Pass in a sub-agent to your sub-agent.
Okay, create a sub agent.
Add it as a soup, like, provide it to some supervisor.
Take that supervisor, create a super supervisor, and provide that supervisor to the super, supervisor.
Okay, this will create a hierarchy of multiple agents.
Other people got pull requests without adding tool.
Because we also have certain agent that has access to tools,
Stochastically.
They were at an advantage where
Their model was able to identify that.
If my documentation agent does not have
Access to my…
PR tool, my code review agent should have access to it.
So let me just create it.
Okay?
That's how they did it.
For my use case, it was very simple.
I wanted one supervisor agent,
that could manage everyone. And I knew that.
To perform anything on GitHub.
I can use…
These specialized… let's say, first, I would
Map my business to some workflow.
I will see what workflow.
That business follows.
I saw that for my business, I needed these specialized tasks.
Okay, so for each task,
I can create an isolated agent that can perform that task.
And provide the response to the supervisor.
That's how I came up with this idea.
Is it always required to convert agent, sub-agents to tools?
Can't we give sub-agents to supervisor agent without tool?
We can do it, but for that, we would need to use a middleware from
Deep Agent Framework.
Okay? There are multiple ways to do this.
I showed you the simplest way.
With whatever we have learned so far.
Uh, Karthik, human in the loop, comes in various flavors.
The PR itself is human in the loop.
You understand what I'm trying to say?
Yeah.
So basically, tools are just functions with access to models. The whole system can be considered as function calling and framework of
The workflow is available with LandGraph, and we use it to domestically.
Chaitanya, you have very well understood whatever we have learned so far.
Alright folks, how many of you think this is easy now?
How many of you think this is easy now?
Give me a thumbs up if you think so.
Yeah, Sharak things, yeah, many people.
Awesome. This makes me really happy.
Yeah, that.
You not only learn something complicated, now you think it is easy, that's the best thing.
Awesome, we can go to Slido.
Tony, please edit your wordings, man. It's funny, but it's
It's not ideal for classroom.
Awesome. I see a few questions here.
Just by using the word supervisor, we created the supervisor agent.
I do not see any specific way of establishing the relationship among supervisor subagent
Karthikeyan, you see?
In the supervisor agent.
We have added tools.
Which are agents in themselves.
We established the relationship like this.
If you want…
A definite way to establish the relationship.
I will recommend…
DeepAgent.
Here you will see that you can create sub-agents by passing in JSON.
I did not talk about deep agents here, right? That's why I showed you the simplest method.
But you can have sub-agents like this.
Okay. You can have like
Sub-agents added like this.
You can also add them as a JSON file.
Uh, I'm not able to find that documentation, but you see, yeah, see.
As sub-agents, you can pass in a Python dictionary or JSON file.
With the name, system prompt, description, and all of those things.
Just have patience in later sessions, we'll discover, like, these complex patterns as well.
Okay folks, we can now have Slido quiz. It's time for Slido quiz.
I see a few questions, let me answer them.
Is it the same on industry level as whatever we have built is just small glimpse of real AI projects?
Ashwar, I would say this is
Very at par with what is happening in the industry.
But there are additional things that you will learn that you can add here to make it.
Like, clearly production ready.
Okay.
So…
We are going to release the Swiggy podcast in a while, and you will see that a lot of the things that we
Are going to cover here is is how they are also building agents internally in their team.
How do, how to decide on when to give.
A second instance of LLM to sub-agent, or if agent will get the second instance.
Uh, Gautam, I do not understand your question. Can you rephrase it or can you elaborate a bit more on what you're trying to ask?
Ventro-defined workflow ourselves and went to allow agent to create workflows dynamically, what's the trade-off?
Uh, Sharath, you define workflows yourself when you have a clear idea of what that workflow would look like.
If that workflow has a lot of static steps.
Then you define it yourself. But if the workflow is very dynamic,
Which requires decisions to be made.
While the workflow is running.
While if the decisions are to be made while the workflow is running.
At that time, you will try to make it agentic.
So your agent, which has a brain, which is the LLM.
Can think and make those decisions on the go.
Okay?
Worked for me. Awesome, Poojan.
First, you can finish off the nuggets. Okay, uh, final, I'll share those things first.
Give me a second.
So there are a few things.
Let me quickly share my screen.
Folks, if you have further questions, ask it on Discord.
We'll be able to answer there.
So how do you ensure reliability in this kind of agents?
Because 1 bad output can break the whole system, right?
So, if your agent is executing like this and there is your coordinator chose one wrong route.
Then, the complete workflow.
Like, the whole output will completely change. So your agentic system will not be much reliable.
To fix it, you can enforce structured output.
So, this is where states come in.
And LandGraph provides it to you.
So, you can have structured outputs in form of states.
You can add validation gates between agents.
Okay, so between each agent execution.
You can add middlewares into agents, which we are going to learn.
In one of the coming lectures.
Through those middlewares, you can add validation layers.
Now that you know LangChain, well, I will share a harness engineering video from YouTube.
Please watch it so you can add those kind of validations.
To ensure that the agent has worked well.
Rather than believing everything that it says.
You can cap the number of retries that the agent makes.
And you can also add some kind of a
Back off. Back off means that…
Uh, you can slow down, you can add timeouts, you can.
Push the agent not to execute further from, uh,
defined stage.
Then state management. How do you ensure that the state
That is that a shared state.
That multiple agents.
will share does not hit a race condition, which means that let's say if agents are parallelly.
Writing or reading from the same state.
How do you ensure that?
It does not hit a race condition.
The, the most…
Easiest way is to add some kind of a checkpointing.
Or some kind of a memory, okay?
While it is being accessed by one agent,
There should be some kind of a check pointer that saves whatever is happening there.
Okay?
Treat all the states as immutable.
So build your pipeline in such a way that you can treat states as immutable.
And design.
Each node to be idempotent.
You all know what idempotent is, right?
Idempotency.
I think whenever you write that, uh…
set, like, create table if not exist.
Right? That's an example of adding potency.
So ensure that all nodes are idempotent, which means
That you do not without right validation, without write.
Like cartels, you do not allow individual nodes to make any updates.
to the state.
Then human in the loop is something that you need to add in agents through multiple.
Ways in our Github agent, we added it through the PR thing. Okay, we always said do not change anything directly without creating a new branch.
We did not say anywhere that create a new branch, right? We just said,
Add documentation and create a PR. That's what we said.
It created new branch on its own, so
Ensure that human in the loop access is present.
Ensure that, uh, whatever repository.
If you're building a voting agent, you are
putting it up on some repository, ensure that.
Just like you block humans from pushing directly onto main, you block your agents as well.
So, follow the principle of least privileges.
Ensure that your
Human in the loop is at place.
Many times, human in the loop
Can go stagnant because agent can keep on waiting for human to respond.
Human might not respond and it can.
So, add timeouts.
Add some kind of a
SLA?
Either like ping the human, right?
Send them an email, whatever.
Uh, on the pending task that they have to review, any agents work.
And define, like, define all of these timeout behaviors upfront.
Do not keep an agent hanging on for human approval.
Okay, this is human in the loop done right.
Add timeout, add auto reject, add escalate, all of these things.
Then security. Security is something very important.
Give your agent boundaries, that is what we did today.
If you see, each agent could only execute certain.
Number of, like, certain number of tools.
Multiple agent could not access, like, all the tools.
That we had. So.
follow the principle of least privilege.
Scope tool permissions rather than giving it to all the agents.
Scope those permissions.
Uh, always treat like
Output from sub-agent as untrusted input.
Okay, add a validation layer. We will see how to do guardrails validation, all of those things using middleware.
This one?
And rather than passing in all the context,
Add some kind of a summarization. You all saw how we added summarization, right?
We use the command method. We passed only the last message from the sub-agent.
Okay, so this is how you add security.
Evaluate your agent. Do not just trust everything.
Add an eval layer, we will learn about evaluation in the coming sessions.
Okay, so combine LLM as a judge and also add heuristic evals.
We are going to learn about both in our evaluation session.
Uh, these are all the nuggets that I had.
I hope, like, most of your questions are also answered through these nuggets.
We can now start the Slido quiz.
Alright, so folks, all of these things, just revisit the session.
Keep this in mind while you are building a production AI system.
I see both my team members are not here.
Are they here?" Ashish Vaikrishna, can any of you take
I'm here.
Yeah. Rakapan, was it too fast?
Folks, do you think today's session was too fast?
No, yeah, no.
It's okay, Rakapan. We do not all have like same pace.
You can revisit the lectures and ask any doubt that you have in Slido.
Augusto, can you take it from… so, Augusto, what I'll do is, I'll ask Ashish Bhai to add these points in
In the resources.
So, he will add these points in the resources as well. So you will have it with you.
Okay.
This was perfect. Setup took time. Best to revisit lectures.
Awesome.
We'll use anti-gravity.
Do not refrain from using AI tools.
Krishna, you can start the quiz.
Yeah.
Gautam, let's revisit this question.
When we talk about routing and all, let's… I think we talked about routing.
Let's revisit this question.
In context engineering, I think.
How does anti-gravity compare to cursor?
I use anti-gravity and Claude Code.
I have not used cursor, Tony, but anybody else who has an opinion can share.
All right, ready for Slido? Folks, do mention in the chat how you liked.
the session today.
Any feedback that you have, whatever.
Alright guys, you can either scan the QR code, or go to slido.com and type out this code. It will take you to the place.
We have Roger Federer in the chat, guys.
Tennis players are also learning AI now.
Oh, CM Vijay.
CR7, we have Ronaldo.
And Dr. Doom also.
Oh, Doctor Loom, singularity.
Yesterday, I met a cohort learner.
He used to name himself Cute.
So QT, okay.
He used to name himself QT.
And yesterday we met, we had a conversation, and he said that, do you know
I was QT in the chat.
A great guy. He built a cool product, so he built a co-pilot that allows you to create agents.
For your company.
So you just pass in documents, you just pass in all of these things, and it will create agents for you.
Great capstone project.
Right, 87 people have joined.
We have 110 people, folks, join fast.
Don't… I think most people are wondering cool names.
To join.
Yeah?
AI Day was great, Srinivas, uh
Release note, I will share the YouTube video link.
You guys can watch it, it was awesome.
We had a great time.
We met so many.
People.
It was live streamed, by the way.
So, you could see…
I'm sharing the link.
All right, yeah, we can start. Krishna, we can start.
Okay, I'll go to the next question.
Which architecture uses multiple AI agents working together to solve complex problems?
Multi-aging system
Multi languages.
Who all remember Naga Arjuna when they see Mas?
So…
Oh.
Yeah, the correct answer is multi-agent system.
We have Syed, Ms. Bogdan, Matta Spider
The lion and Saishira
Let's move on to the next question.
When should the team consider using a multi-agent system?
Let's… yeah, so when the problem can be decomposed into multiple specialized tasks
See?
Now, the Saishira, the lion, and Krishna
Which multi-agent architecture processes tasks in a fixed step-by-step order
The correct answer is sequential pattern
We have Syed, Buddha, Saishira, Mikhpartil, and Dexter
Thank you
Dexter.
What is the…
We have Dexter in the chat, guys, be careful.
What is the primary role of a coordinator agent?
To dynamically route work to the appropriate subagents
We have
Syed Gupta Saishira, Amit Pattelaamakrishna
Let's see…
In Hydar task decomposition, what happens to a large task?
I think that Jeff answers the question itself.
Yeah, so it is broken into smaller subtasks handled by sub-agents.
We have Syed Mota Saishira, Amit Bhattan Krishna
Okay, last question guys
Which statement best describes the trade-off of multi-agent systems
The answer is the improve accuracy for complex tasks often at a higher capacity
Let's see
Oh, congratulations, Syed. Sai Muktar, Dexter, and Amit Pathil nextor came out of nowhere.
So I recently exchanged answers, like, maybe.
All right, awesome. Thank you, everyone.
Ask me if you have any questions, if you have any thoughts, just share it.
Is there a mental model to decide
How to scope agents in multi-agent setup?
I'm drawing parallels to microservice architecture DDD.
Uh…
Again, I think I already discussed this.
You take a business problem, you see.
What?
What isolated pieces of, or what specialized tasks you can have.
You usually, like, distinguish agents based on their specialization.
Just like in an orc, where do you decide that, okay, this is the limit.
of the job of a product manager, this is the limit of the job of a
Programmer, this is the limit of the job of an architect.
Whoever have got the job from CodeBasics, did they ever share how did learning things help them get a job as well as worked on real projects that they face any difficulty?
You know what I'm thinking? I'm thinking to bring in people.
from past cohort.
Who got a job in one of the sessions that we may have.
So maybe we can coordinate it. I think that could be useful.
To you?
But I can't promise this, but let me try, let me try.
Doing this, okay? Because it relies on so many factors. Let me try doing this.
I think that would help you all a lot.
So I'll give it a shot.
Yes, Yasmin, you are welcome to stay, but if you have to leave somewhere, it's okay, we are just going to chat now, I think.
It's done.
Uh, Gautam, we, we.
We realized that we could not adjust the time, but we could conduct office hour sessions.
For folks who are at SF, like, who are in SF, who are in…
on the other side of the world.
For whomever it is really early, we can come up with a
Uh, with a time where we can schedule an office hour session.
And in that session, even if you miss something and if you have some doubts.
We will try to cover it, ok, it can be on weekdays.
Some weekday?
Ashish Vai, can you please share a poll?
In Discord to identify the
Time for office hour sessions?
It should align with the CEST time or PSG time.
Shimesh, I cannot promise that.
But Discord is always open.
You can get anything.
Bharat, it's okay to be overwhelmed. You have the whole week.
I, I can promise you that.
If you revise it a few times,
It will be, it will seem super easy to you.
Okay, just…
All you need is revision in practice.
Trust me.
Thank you, Ringanathan.
Thanks, Vinay. Thanks, Santosh.
Uh, by the way, after…
After I'm telling you…
After completing the whole cohort, you will be added into alumni
Yeah, alumni chat.
Where you will find all the people where earlier.
Oh, congratulations, Raishma.
All right, I think we can.
Ringanathan, yeah, that we will, I'm telling you.
Okay, let's discuss this.
I'm going to the website, I'm going to show you the schedule.
This is the whole curriculum, right?
When we talk about capstone project,
This week, week 8.
We will give you break after week 8.
Do you know why? Because it will buy you enough time to work on Capstone as well.
Okay, it will give you.
day to work on Capstone as well.
So after, like,
Session 15 and 16.
After week 8, we can think of a break.
Awesome.
Alright, thank you everyone.
Thank you for joining. I think that's it for today.
Uh, we can…
Conclude this now.
Alright, see you next week. Build your agents. Remember, I want to see
Some demos next week, okay? Bring me some demos next week.